# Luke Floden

## Senior Fullstack Web Developer

luke.floden@gmail.com • 502-498-7818 • lukefloden.me

#### CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 5+ years with startups in the healthcare and sustainability sectors

Skill Highlight 3+ years building web applications with React/Laravel

Leadership Project lead of distributed teams and mentoring junior developers

Languages Typescript, React, SvelteKit, Laravel Tools Sentry, Fly.io, Vercel, AWS, GCP

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cadence OneFive New York, NY

Lead Software Engineer

05/2024 - 11/2024

Technologies: Laravel, Livewire, Alpine.js, Vite, Tailwind

- Led development team of 4 across 5 time-zones
  - Introduced weekly demos with stakeholders, re-aligning a project already 50% past its original timeline
- Responsible for site-wide UI design overhaul
  - Reducing 1000s of lines of copy-pasted code
  - Increased mobile support: Improving functionality and readability across 5 screen sizes
  - Fixing broken accessibility features: Loading/focus styles, keyboard navigation, fixing incorrect HTML
- Upgraded an aging, monolithic codebase
  - Saving 5+ developer hours weekly by transitioning from Webpack to Vite.
  - Eliminated source of frequent bugs: fixing component lifecycle management with an upgrade to Livewire 3
- Introduced automated linting/formatting to front and back end
  - Surfacing 20+ pages with broken HTML: addressing long-standing UI bugs
  - Reducing pull request burden by shrinking lines changed by 50%

Senior Software Engineer (contract)

02/2024 - 05/2024

- Led redesign of primary user flow
  - Brought cohesion to the design system, implementing changes in Figma
  - Optimized navigation UX: Providing <100ms response times to user's input (INP Core Web Vital)</li>
- Co-led with CEO the process of acquiring a UI designer: Responsible for ultimate hiring decision.
- Made myself indispensable during contract period and took on lead/PM role upon promotion.

Curai Health Palo Alto, CA

Software Engineer III

09/2022 - 06/2023

Technologies: React (Native), TanStack, Redux, FastAPI, Flask

- Developed cross-platform apps with over 20,000 downloads
  - Owned payment/paywall features: Planning, design, implementation, and A/B testing
  - Optimized state management with transition from Redux to TanStack Query
- Designed/implemented external typescript SDK+API
  - Minimally invasive to main product: utilizing cross-document messaging and custom routing

Software Engineer II 01/2022 - 09/2022

- Designed and Created an authenticated business-partner portal; with instant validation and user feedback
  - Integrated with Slack: aiding growth team in prompt outreach
- Kicked off a project for an external gateway service: managing gradual migration to microservices across 4 development teams
  - Championed Automated documentation and endpoint data type-safety through FastAPI
- Promoted to Software Engineer III, joining the core patient app team

## Machine Learning Engineering Intern

09/2021 - 12/2021

- Developed an interactive data analysis tool for machine learning model pipelines (React + dc.js)
  - Early detection of bias and safeguards surrounding the demographics of our users.
  - Integrated into CICD with automated tests and generated reports.
  - Conducted user-studies to guide design of UX.

## Justice AV Solutions

Louisville, KY

Software Engineer

01/2018 - 08/2019

Technologies: C#, .NET

- Developed networked audio/video desktop applications interfacing with custom in-house hardware.
- Pursued a Masters of Engineering instead of accepting offer of continued employment

## EDUCATION, ACCREDITATIONS, & HONORS

University of Louisville: J.B. Speed School of Engineering

2021

Masters of Engineering in Computer Science Engineering

Kentucky Colonel - Commissioned by Governor Ernie Fletcher

2007

- Honorary title granted for noteworthy service and accomplishments
- One of Kentucky's highest honors, dating back to 1813